<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OpenGL on Liam Bessell</title>
    <link>https://lbess.github.io/techs/opengl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OpenGL on Liam Bessell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Liam Bessell</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://lbess.github.io/techs/opengl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>N-Body Simulation</title>
      <link>https://lbess.github.io/portfolio/nbody-simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lbess.github.io/portfolio/nbody-simulation/</guid>
      <description>Video presentation
Github repository
N-Body Problem How do we simulate the movement of n-bodies when each body affects every other body? Examples: Gravitational forces on stars, network visualization, molecular dynamics, and more.
Naive Simulation Before attempting the Barnes-Hut simulation I first implemented the much easier Naive n-body simulation. I quickly discovered that the Naive simulation couldn&amp;rsquo;t effectively run simulations with more than ~2000 bodies in real time. This is actually what kindled my interest in pursuing Barnes-Hut; I wanted to see massive galaxies move around in real time!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deferred Renderer</title>
      <link>https://lbess.github.io/portfolio/deferred-renderer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lbess.github.io/portfolio/deferred-renderer/</guid>
      <description>The final project in my computer graphics was to implement dynamic geometry, deferred rendering, and bloom in OpenGL. I went on to extend this project with tiled-deferred rendering as well.
Dynamic Geometry There are various geometrical objects with transformations in this project, including: bouncing spheres, surfaces of revolution that deform, rotating bunnies, and shearing teapots.
Deferred Rendering Instead of having one rendering pass whereby the scene is rendered directly to the screen, in deferred rendering we have two passes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raytracer</title>
      <link>https://lbess.github.io/portfolio/raytracer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lbess.github.io/portfolio/raytracer/</guid>
      <description>One of the projects in my computer graphics class was to create an offline ray tracer from scratch in C++.
Technical Details This was a difficult yet immensely rewarding project. It was difficult in that I started from scratch and had to learn how light behaves in the real world in order to simulate it accurately. One skillset among many you quickly sharpen in computer graphics is math, specifically with regards to linear algebra and vectors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>